healthspan.co.uk 2018-09-02

# Privacy policy | Healthspan

This Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand why we collect and retain your data. It also provides details on how to access and update your information. Healthspan uses and stores your data for fulfilling a contract to you and for marketing , with your consent. You may withdraw consent to marketing or restrict processing at any time. 

**Who are we?**

Healthspan Ltd (and Healthspan (UK) Ltd) is a private company selling high quality vitamins, minerals, supplements and other nutrition and wellbeing products direct to our customers. Healthspan is registered as a Data Controller with the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner in Guernsey (01481 742074 [https://dataci.gg](https://dataci.gg/)).

**What do we collect?**

To enable us to process your order we will ask you to provide personal details such as:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Password
  * Address and telephone number
  * IP Addresses and Cookies 

We also store some observed data such as your browsing history or click through email behaviours. We may also group customers depending upon their geographical location or sales behaviour.

**NutriCoach Mobile App**

Healthspan’s personalised nutrition app collects (in addition to your personal data already listed above) activity data, weight, sleep activity, heart rate, geographical location, date of birth and eating habits as provided by you. This is necessary to enable the app services; however you can withdraw consent at any time by contacting us.

**What do we do with your data?**

We use the data we store to fulfil your orders and send you personalised, relevant communications regarding our product and services.

Healthspan will never pass or sell your data outside the Healthspan Group of companies except where that third party requires the data to provide order delivery, or to provide communications as part of Healthspan’s normal service, including marketing analytics. For more information about who we share your data with, read on. 

We share your data with our trusted fulfilment partners and ensure all appropriate contractual safeguards and security is in place. These include warehouse packing services, IT systems, hosting providers and IT support to fulfil your order; mailing houses and email services to send you marketing (where you have permitted us to) and marketing analysis third parties including an independent product and service review provider.

_We may send information outside of Europe and Guernsey where we use a service provider or technology provider based overseas. ( e.g NutriCoach support based in the USA) .Where we send personal data outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") we will ensure that suitable safeguards are in place to protect the information. For example, these safeguards might include: Using the model contractual clauses provided by the European Commission or other relevant contractual safeguards; The European Commission deciding that the country or international organisation has an adequate level of personal data protection. ( e.g Guernsey)_

_Your data will be kept for a period of 10 years after your last interaction with us. We need to keep transaction information for auditing and statutory reporting purposes for this period, however we can remove you from our marketing database at your request._

We use cookies on our website – partly to provide basic web services and partly to help us monitor and track website usage through Google Analytics. We do, from time to time, use cookies to allow us to better target adverts to website users. You can read more in our Cookie policy:

By using the Site you consent to us using the cookies described below.

### Cookies

**First Party Cookies**

First party cookies are used to retain your basket selection and help us to remember your browsing history, product and information preferences. We use cookies to enable you to add products to your shopping basket. We also use first party cookies to help us balance our servers. This allows us to deliver quick page load times for our customers.

Healthspan’s first party cookies contain no personally identifiable information. All personally identifiable Information on browsing, preference and purchase history, is stored in our secure website data base. This information is collected for our internal purposes only and shall not be disclosed to any other organization except as required by law.

**Third Party Cookies**

Third party cookies are cookies that pass on information on browsing and purchase activity to third party service providers.

Healthspan primarily uses third party cookies to help us conduct website tracking and monitoring to ensure we provide our customers with the best possible shopping and web experience. We use the web analytics platform provided by Google called Google Analytics.

We will also intermittently use third party cookies to gather behavioural, browsing and demographic data. This information is used by third party partners to deliver marketing and advertising activities. 

**Blocking Cookies**

We understand that people have different privacy concerns. You can choose not to receive a cookie file by enabling your web browser to refuse cookies or to prompt you before you accept a cookie.

Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our website will issue cookies onto your device. Please note that if you refuse to accept certain cookies, some of the functions on the Healthspan Sites such as adding a product to a basket may not work.

By agreeing to these terms and conditions you are accepting the use of first and third party cookies on and by the Healthspan websites.

Further information about cookies can be found by clicking on the following links;

<http://www.ico.gov.uk/>

**Credit or Debit Cards**

Healthspan does not process or store credit or debit card information once your transaction is complete. All card payments are securely processed by our payment gateway provider CyberSource which then provides Healthspan with a token to take future payments or apply refunds.

**Your Rights**

If you would like a copy of the personal data we hold about you, please contact us and ask for a ‘subject access request’. We will require you to verify your identity.

You have the right to object to processing that is likely to cause or is causing damage or distress and decisions being taken by automated means.

You have the right to have inaccurate personal data rectified or removed – if you would like to do so please contact us on customercare@healthspan.co.uk or call 08007312377.

You have the right to have data removed where Healthspan does not have a legal basis to retain this information for example for accounting and auditing purposes.

You have the right to stop direct marketing at any time (just opt out using [My Account](https://www.healthspan.co.uk/your-account) or let us know by calling FREEPHONE 0800 73 123 77 or email customercare@healthspan.co.uk).

Your data will be disclosed where obliged by law to do so.

Healthspan has appointed a Data Protection Officer, Katie Hutchins, who you may contact via DPO@healthspan.co.uk

**How secure is your data?**

Healthspan employs a wide variety of security measures to back up, protect and manage your data. We are audited annually and undertake to secure your data as much as possible using up to date technology and robust policies and processes. All third parties are scrutinised and subject to appropriate contractual safeguards. We document all data processing and review this regularly. Staff are regularly trained on security and policies and we use strict access controls.

**Reviews, ratings, promotions and competitions**

To leave a Product rating or review you must have purchased that Product.

All reviews are collected by Feefo, an independent review engine. Healthspan do not vet poor reviews – but may respond directly to them.

The poster continues to own all rights to content provided to Healthspan. However Healthspan reserves the right to use this content royalty free as part of its marketing and communication programs.

The purpose of reviews is to help people who haven’t brought the product to learn from the experiences of those that have.

**Updates to this Policy**

This policy may be updated from time to time in line with current legislation and best practices.

Last amended date: 26/06/2018
